monaviemediacenter.com 2014-03-30

# MonaVie Privacy Policy | MonaVie

**Last updated: October 10, 2013**

MonaVie is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring the security of the information you submit to us. This privacy policy applies to www.monavie.com and www.monavievo.com owned and operated by MonaVie. We want your use of the MonaVie web sites and the services we offer to be productive and safe and we have taken great efforts to keep your information confidential and secure at all times within our system. Our Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine quality products and services with integrity in dealing with our users.  Our Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services. MonaVie’s Privacy Policy illustrates our commitment to your privacy and security.

MonaVie has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information.  TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. This privacy policy covers the collection and use of data through the web sites www.monavie.com, www.monavievo.com (collectively the “MonaVie Sites”).  
If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Kelli Knight at legal@monavie.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. MonaVie complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. Information regarding the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor Framework can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>.

**What Personal Information We Collect**  
The MonaVie Sites each have different functions and collect different types of personal information (PI) such as name, address, email address and phone number. Additionally, www.monavievo.com allow you to order products and manage your distributorship. Generally, you can visit the MonaVie Sites without entering any PII. However, if you choose to place an order on the MonaVie Sites, we require that you provide your name, mailing address, billing address, email address, phone number, credit card number and its expiration date. All of this information is necessary for us to complete the transaction and notify you of your order status.

The purpose of www.monavievo.com is to manage your distributorship, preferred customers and entire network. In order to use www.monavievo.com, you must have a Distributor Login provided by MonaVie. When enrolling to become a MonaVie distributor and thereby obtain access to www.monavievo.com, we collect your PII, including your name, home or business address, telephone numbers, email address, IP address, credit card number and expiration date, bank account information (for direct deposit or direct debit), and various government-issued identifying data, including, but not limited to, your passport number, tax identification number, national ID card number, social insurance number, etc. We may also collect scanned copies of government-issued photo I.D.’s. This data is necessary to manage your MonaVie distributorship for purposes of identifying who you are, placement of your distributorship and of downline distributorships in the personal enrollment tree and the placement tree, compliance management, product ordering, recognition and rewards, and bonus calculation and payment. We permit your upline to see only your name. We permit your sponsor to see your name, email address and phone number. We also collect third party personal information from preferred customers, including their name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number and expiration date. This PII is used to charge for product orders and ship product and for no other purposes.

**Tell-A-Friend and Address Book**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site/product or share your Wishlist, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. MonaVie Sites do not store this information.

  To facilitate shipping your orders to your friends, we provide an Address Book for you to enter your contacts. We will ask you for your friend’s name, address and telephone number. We will only use this information for the specific reason for which it was provided to us.

**Supplementation of Information**  
In order to protect your account, we may on occasion supplement the personal information you submitted to us with information from third party sources. We use services from leaders in the industry to verify your identity, in order to prevent others from defrauding your account or the company.

**Testimonials/Product Reviews**  
If you provide a testimonial or product review on the MonaVie Sites, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  For testimonials, we do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting his or her name and video testimonial. If you enter a comment in a public forum we are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these comments. If you want to remove your personal information that is being displayed on our website under public pages, please contact us at [privacy@monavie.com](mailto:privacy@monavie.com).

  **How We Use Your Information**  
We may use your email address, mailing address and/or phone number to provide quality customer support or to reach you regarding order status, product or fulfillment issues and other customer service related activities. We may use your email address, mailing address and/or phone number to contact you regarding new product offerings, newsletters and other aspects of your use of the MonaVie Sites. If, however, you do not wish to receive such communications, you have the ability to "opt-out" at any time and you will not be contacted further.  
From time to time, we may ask you to answer surveys regarding current or future MonaVie products, as well as to determine hours worked at each rank in the compensation plan. Participation in these surveys is always optional. Survey responses are only used in the aggregate, and are never linked to an individual. While our survey data is primarily for use within monavievo.com only, we may occasionally share the aggregate survey data with our affiliates and development partners in order to facilitate new product development and improve customer service and overall customer satisfaction.

  **Information Sharing**  
MonaVie is not an "information broker." We do not engage in the selling of the profile, contact, web usage habits, behavior, buying patterns, or demographic information of our customers, partners or users. We use the information we collect about you to process orders, pay bonuses and provide the best and most personalized service possible. We may revise this Privacy Policy occasionally, so please check it frequently. MonaVie does not share, sell, rent, or trade PII with third parties other than as described in this privacy policy.

**Agents/Service Providers**  
We use third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. We use Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order. When you purchase a product and use our site, we will share your name, address, telephone number, and email address as necessary for the third party to provide that service. These third parties are prohibited from using your personal information for promotional purposes.

**Business Transition**  
In the event MonaVie goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personal information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
In addition to the circumstances described above, MonaVie may disclose or release information when we, in good faith, believe that doing so is reasonably necessary: (i) to comply with the law, judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site; (ii) to enforce or apply the terms of User Agreement; or (iii) to protect the rights, property or safety of MonaVie Sites, our users, or others.

**Links to Other Sites**  
This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by MonaVie. Please be aware that we, MonaVie, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site.

**Social Media Widgets**  
Our web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Tracking Information**  
MonaVie does not track users of MonaVie Sites online activity over time or allow other parties to do this on our Site.

**Log Files**  
Like most every web site, the MonaVie Sites record certain tracking information any time someone visits the site. For every web page that is viewed, our web server records an IP address, the operating system, browser version and the name of the page that was viewed. We use a third-party tracking service that uses tracking technologies to track non-personal information about visitors to our site. This information is not linked to any specific user and is used in the aggregate to maintain, track performance and improve the MonaVie Sites.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a small piece of information that is stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. The MonaVie Sites use cookies for the sole purpose of uniquely identifying our users and securing their personal information. We also use cookies to track your order process without requiring reentry or re-verification of password or personal information on each page of the site. Rather than storing this information on MonaVie's server, the cookie is stored in your computer and is activated only when you visit the MonaVie Sites. Your privacy and security are not compromised when you accept a cookie from the MonaVie Sites. No one can access the information except MonaVie.

**Third Party Tracking Technologies**  
Some of our business partners use cookies on our site. We do not have access or control over these cookies.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
We may employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information.

We may use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see “Choice and Opt-out.”

**Flash LSOs**  
Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use Flash cookies to collect and store information.

Flash cookies are different from browser cookies because of the amount of, type of, and how data is stored.  Cookie management tools provided by your browser will not remove Flash cookies.  To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:   
<http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118>

**Data Retention**  
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services and will use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. ****

**Email & "Opt Out" Policy**  
We may use your email address provided to contact you regarding the following:  
1\. User Registration Status (including confirmation of account signup);  
2\. Order Status and Shipping Notification  
3\. Online Customer Satisfaction Survey  
4\. Major changes to the website, addition of new products or services;  
5\. Promotional and marketing materials that we think you may find useful.

If you desire not to receive information about products or services we think may be of interest, you can change the notification options in your account settings. If you wish to not receive any of these emails, you may opt-out by submitting your email address to support@monavie.com or by following the unsubscribe instructions within each email communication.

**Protecting Your Personal Information**  
The MonaVie Sites use secure sockets layer (SSL) to encrypt the transfer of sensitive information, such as your account password and billing information including credit card, from your web browser to our web server. Only the last four (4) digits of your credit card number will be displayed in your account. When you place an Order with us, you are given an opportunity to select if you wish to have your credit card numbers stored on our system. Emails you send to us may not be secure unless otherwise told that security measures will be in place prior to your transmitting the information. For this reason, we ask that you do not send confidential information such as credit card numbers or account numbers to us through emails.

The same SSL protocol also acts to authenticate the MonaVie Sites and prevent unauthorized "hackers" from masquerading as any of our sites while you are logged in to your account. This is accomplished through a "digital certificate", which is an unforgettable electronic "identity card".  
If another website attempts to falsely identify itself as a MonaVie site, your web browser will display a warning indicating that there is a problem with the digital certificate for www.monavievo.com [or mvie.nl]. Do not log in to those sites if you see any such warning.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [privacy@monavie.com](mailto:privacy@monavie.com).  

**Updating Your Personal Information**  
Preferred customers and distributors can update or correct their personal information at any time by visiting the "My Account" section of the MonaVie Sites. If you wish to access, delete or correct your information, please send us an email to distributorsupport@monavie.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. Requests for access will be responded to within 30 days of the request.

**Changes in this Privacy Policy**  
By using our web site, you consent to the collection and use of information by MonaVie as described in this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy policy, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions regarding MonaVie’s privacy policy and practices, please direct them  
Mail to:  
MonaVie LLC.  
Attention: Legal Department  
10855 South River Front PKWY, suite 100  
South Jordan, Utah 84095  
Email to: privacy@monavie.com
